It's the way you look.
Brzydzę się tobą.
I can't stand the way you look.
Nie mogę na ciebie patrzeć.
You look so…
Wyglądasz tak…
Calm down, Shinichi.
Spokojnie, Shinichi.
We're in trouble if you're short of breath when we have to fight.
Musisz panować nad oddechem na wypadek walki.
I know.
Wiem.
I would have liked to have discussed many things with you both,
Chciałabym omówić z wami wiele tematów,
but I have a bad feeling about this,
ale mam złe przeczucie, więc nie będę tego przeciągać.
I've killed 38 so far.
Do tej pory zabiłam 38 osób.
Mainly as food,
Głównie dla pożywienia.
but I believe my numbers are on the low end among my kind.
To niewielka liczba w porównaniu do moich pobratymców.
I could supplement the lack with normal food humans eat.
Wszelkie braki suplementowałam normalną ludzką żywnością.
In other words,
Zmierzam do tego,
parasites can survive without eating humans.
że pasożyty mogą przetrwać bez pożerania ludzi.
I have also done much research on humans.
Bacznie przyglądałam się ludziom.
What are we parasites to humans,
Czym pasożyty są dla ludzi
and what are humans to us?
i czym ludzie są dla nas?
My conclusion is this.
Oto moje wnioski:
We are two halves of the same whole.
jesteśmy dwiema połówkami jednej całości. Stanowimy jedną rodzinę.
We are the children of the human race.
Jesteśmy dziećmi rasy ludzkiej.
What? What are you talking about?
Co ty pleciesz?
Cut the crap!
Daruj sobie!
That's fine.
Biorąc pod uwagę ludzkie emocje, rozumiem, że ciężko ci to zaakceptować.
However, we are fragile.
Jesteśmy słabi.
We are merely a life form that cannot survive on its own.
Nie potrafimy przetrwać samodzielnie.
So don't bully us.
Więc nie dręczcie nas.
"Bully"?
„Nie dręczcie”?
Look who's talking!
I kto to mówi.
You two are very rare beings.
Wy dwaj jesteście wyjątkowymi istotami.
That is why I wanted you to know my thoughts.
Dlatego chciałam, żebyście poznali moje przemyślenia.
While I'm at it, a word of advice.
Mam też dla was radę.
About Gotou, the man who recently pursued you,
Dotyczącą Gotou, mężczyzny, który was ostatnio ścigał.
don't fight him.
Nie walczcie z nim.
If it had been Gotou instead of Miki from the beginning,
Gdyby to on kontrolował tamto ciało zamiast Mikiego,
you would be dead by now.
już byście nie żyli.
Probably.
Prawdopodobnie.
He is indeed one of our "fragile" kind that I created through experimentation,
Choć należy do naszego „słabego” gatunku, stworzyłam go w wyniku eksperymentu.
but he is invincible.
Jest niepokonany.
You're contradicting yourself.
Przeczysz sama sobie.
She's laughing!
Śmieje się!
And regarding the other one, the mayor, Hirokawa…
A jeśli chodzi o burmistrza, Hirokawę…
Izumi Shinichi?
Izumi Shinichi?
I think that's the detective, Hirama.
To chyba ten detektyw, Hirama.
Wait. So are they all cops?
Oni wszyscy są gliniarzami?
At a glance, they look like a nondescript mother holding a baby
Matka trzymająca dziecko
and a boy who had found a parasite's victim
i chłopak, który znalazł ofiarę pasożytów, ale został skreślony z listy podejrzanych.
Even if we'd seen them separately here immediately
Nawet gdybyśmy zobaczyli ich tu osobno
following a murder,
zaraz po morderstwie,
I would not have felt this much conviction.
nie byłbym tak pewny jak teraz.
Izumi Shinichi.
Izumi Shinichi.
There's something more to him.
On coś w sobie ma.
And this is her, the parasite, Tamura Reiko!
A to ten pasożyt, Tamura Reiko!
AUTHOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
AUTOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
MORE THAN HUMAN
WIĘCEJ NIŻ CZŁOWIEK
The baby's clothes have some of my blood on them.
Jego ubranko jest poplamione krwią.
Wait! Don't come any closer!
Nie zbliżajcie się!
Tamura-san.
Tamura-san.
You are Tamura Reiko-san, correct?
Pani nazywa się Tamura Reiko, prawda?
No.
Nie.
You killed the man named Kuramori just now!
Przed chwilą zabiła pani Kuramoriego.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Nic o tym nie wiem.
I'll ask someone else.
Spytam kogoś innego.
Ikeda-kun!
Ikeda-kun!
Why are you here?
Co tu robisz?
We've met before. You remember me, don't you?
Już się poznaliśmy. Pamiętasz, prawda?
If you are the same person I met back then,
Jeśli jesteś tą samą osobą,
you should be able to say my name.
powinieneś znać moje nazwisko.
Who am I, Ikeda-kun?
Jak się nazywam, Ikeda-kun?
Did you forget my name, Hirama-san?
Zapomniał pan moje imię, Hirama-san?
It seems that one's human.
On jest człowiekiem.
So, you seem very calm, Tamura-san.
Jest pani bardzo spokojna, Tamura-san.
I think you're mistaking me for someone else.
Pomyliliście mnie z kimś innym.
At this distance,
Z takiej odległości
even this should be able to find its mark.
trafimy bez problemu.
This isn't funny!
To nie jest śmieszne.
You people are all crazy!
Odebrało wam rozum!
I would be deeply sorry if I were wrong, but I'm afraid I have no choice.
Bardzo mi przykro, ale nie mam wyjścia.
I can't risk getting any closer.
Nie mogę ryzykować.
Everyone keep your eyes peeled when I fire this shot!
Bądźcie czujni, kiedy wystrzelę.
I'll take full responsibility!
Biorę na siebie odpowiedzialność.
Please stop!
Przestańcie!
What are you doing?
Co wy robicie?
Hirama-san.
Hirama-san.
Well done.
Brawo.
You were correct.
Miałeś rację.
Fire!
Ognia!
Stop! The baby is human!
Nie! Dziecko jest człowiekiem!
Izumi Shinichi, stay back!
Izumi Shinichi, nie zbliżaj się!
Shinichi! Get back!
Shinichi, cofnij się!
But…
Ale…
No way.
Niemożliwe.
You're not involved, right, Izumi-kun?
Izumi-kun, to nie możesz być ty.
There's no way Izumi-kun is there!
Nie może go tam być.
No way! I've had enough!
Nie! Mam dość!
I'm done!
Kończę z tym!
What's the matter?
Co jest?
Why won't she retaliate?
Dlaczego nie atakuje?
She's coming toward us!
Idzie w naszą stronę.
She must have something in mind! Get back, Shinichi!
Na pewno coś knuje. Cofnij się.
Run away!
Uciekaj.
Shinichi.
Shinichi.
Wait, Shinichi.
Poczekaj, Shinichi.
I can't have you run away right now.
Nie możesz teraz uciec.
How can I…
Jak mogę…
How can I speak to your humanity?
Jak mogę przemówić do twojej ludzkiej strony?
Shinichi.
Shinichi.
Mom.
Mamo.
Don't be duped, Shinichi! It's a trap!
Nie daj się nabrać. To pułapka!
Remember! Remember the hole in your heart!
Pomyśl o swym złamanym sercu.
No.
Nie.
Stop! Stop fire!
Wstrzymać ogień!
Stop!
Przestańcie.
You'll hit the boy!
Traficie chłopca.
Something's not right.
Coś jest nie tak.
I've been thinking for a long while.
Długo o tym myślałam.
For what purpose was I born into this world?
W jakim celu trafiłam na ten świat?
Whenever I resolved one question, another would arise in its place.
Po poznaniu odpowiedzi na jedno pytanie zaraz pojawiało się drugie.
I sought the beginning.
Szukałam początku.
I sought the end.
Szukałam końca.
I've just been walking and walking, thinking all the while.
Chodziłam tak bez celu, myśląc.
Perhaps nothing will change, no matter how far I go.
Być może nic się nie zmieni, dokąd bym się nie udała.
If I'm to stop my journey, that is fine, too.
Być może muszę przerwać swą podróż.
Even if I were informed that everything has reached its end,
Jeśli to ma być koniec,
I'd just accept it.
zaakceptuję to.
But even so,
Poznałam dziś odpowiedź na jedno z moich pytań.
Shinichi, this child.
Shinichi, to dziecko…
In the end, I didn't do anything to it.
W końcu nic z nim nie zrobiłam.
The child is a normal human being.
To zwyczajny człowiek.
Raise the child by human hands, to lead a normal life.
Niech wychowają go ludzie, żeby miał normalne życie.
Okay.
Okej.
Don't worry.
Nie martw się.
Thank you.
Dziękuję.
"Thank you"?
„Dziękuję”?
I recently imitated a human, laughing out loud in front of a mirror.
Niedawno ćwiczyłam przed lustrem ludzki śmiech.
It felt rather pleasant.
To było całkiem przyjemne.
She's dead?
Nie żyje?
She's dead.
Nie żyje.
Impossible.
Niemożliwe.
Why?
Dlaczego?
You could've fought if you wanted to.
Mogła walczyć.
Fled, even.
A nawet uciec.
Are you sad?
Jesteś smutny?
Of course. Your mom is dead.
Oczywiście. Twoja mama nie żyje.
Dead.
Nie żyje.
Mom is dead.
Twoja mama nie żyje.
Mom.
Mamo.
Shinichi.
Shinichi.
Are you all right, Shinichi?
Wszystko w porządku?
Did any oil get on you?
Oparzyłeś się olejem?
Meet the one who opened that hole again.
Spotkaj się z osobą, która wydrążyła dziurę w twoim sercu.
It's dead.
Nie żyje.
Its heart stopped.
Jego serce przestało bić.
A dream so embarrassing,
Ten sen był bardzo nieprzyzwoity
I could never tell anyone.
i nie mogłam nikomu o nim powiedzieć
They're dead.
Oni nie żyją.
They're all dead.
Wszyscy nie żyją.
Life.
Życie.
Life will return to this tree.
Życie powróci do tego drzewa.
Shinichi-kun!
Shinichi-kun!
You'll come back, right?
Wrócisz, prawda?
We're home.
Wróciliśmy.
Welcome back.
Witajcie w domu.
What's wrong, Shinichi?
Co się stało, Shinichi?
I just had a really sad dream.
Miałem bardzo smutny sen.
Izumi-kun.
Izumi-kun.
Shinichi-kun.
Shinichi-kun.
Are you back?
Wróciłeś?
My tears are…
Moje łzy…
Satomi.
Satomi.
How's Izumi-kun?
Jak tam Izumi-kun?
I think he should be able to come back to school soon.
Niedługo powinien wrócić do szkoły.
I see.
Świetnie.
What happened?
Co się stało?
He's been absent since the day he just up and went home.
Nie było go, odkąd wyszedł wtedy z lekcji.
I'm sure there's a lot going on. Let's go.
Na pewno ma sporo na głowie. Chodźmy.
What happened in that park didn't even make the news.
Media nie mówiły o tym, co zaszło w parku.
But…
Ale…
Izumi-kun came back.
Izumi-kun wrócił.
He came back!
Wrócił!
Okay, you can have lunch in this room.
Możesz tu zjeść.
WAITING ROOM
POCZEKALNIA
How was it?
Jak było?
I'm tired.
Jestem zmęczony.
I think he's a tad too composed for someone his age.
Jest wyjątkowo ułożony jak na nastolatka.
You're right that he's unusually poised in some ways,
Racja, jest dość spokojny.
but there are kids like him.
Zdarzają się takie dzieci.
But I don't think he has that ability the detectives are hoping for.
Ale nie sądzę, by miał umiejętności, na które liczą detektywi.
Not in the same league as that man's, at least.
Na pewno nie tak potężnych jak tamten mężczyzna.
So it's only him, after all?
Więc mamy tylko jego?
Unfortunately.
Niestety.
Dogs, cats.
Psy, koty.
Monkeys, bears, birds.
Małpy, niedźwiedzie, ptaki.
I don't think there's any point in seeing them.
Możemy je sobie darować.
Just shut up and walk.
Zamknij się i idź.
So?
Więc z kim się dziś widzę?
Humans.
Z ludźmi.
Oh, that's great!
Wspaniale!
It means the true test is coming up soon.
To znaczy, że zbliża się prawdziwy sprawdzian.
I see.
Rozumiem.
So you're finally going to believe what I say.
Wreszcie uwierzycie w to, co mówię.
Detective, I'm actually innocent.
Jestem niewinny.
Please believe me!
Musicie mi uwierzyć.
No? That wasn't funny?
Co, nie bawi to was?
Shut your trap!
Zamknij się!
Get his cuffs.
Przypnij go.
Yes?
Tak?
Izumi Shinichi-kun, please come with me again.
Izumi Shinichi-kun, proszę ze mną.
Okay.
Okej.
No matter what they ask me, I will keep Migi's existence hidden.
O co by nie pytali, nie powiem im o Migim.
I should calm myself down, one more time.
Powinienem się uspokoić.
This is the last thing we'll ask of you.
- To ostatnia rzecz, o jaką cię prosimy. - Okej.
Listen, Uragami.
Uragami.
I'm going to have you prove your ability once and for all.
Masz okazję udowodnić, jakie posiadasz umiejętności.
Okay, wait in this room.
Poczekaj tutaj.
When they call your name, please follow instructions.
- Postępuj zgodnie z instrukcjami. - Okej.
I'm going to have you meet five people.
Zobaczysz się z piątką osób.
First, find the one of your "kind" among them.
Musisz ustalić, który z nich jest taki jak ty.
Someone with the same ability as you.
Kto posiada te same umiejętności.
You said you'd know if you met one, right?
Twierdziłeś, że zdołasz go wyczuć.
Yeah, that's right! I can tell!
Owszem.
I think, anyway.
Tak myślę.
Second, let us know if one of their kind is among them.
Po drugie powiadom nas, czy są zainfekowani.
Hey.
Czyli jest wśród nich jeden z tych potworów?
Don't tell me they're just going to troop in here all meek-like! Hey!
Nie mówcie, że po prostu tu sobie wejdą?
Is this glass going to keep me safe?
To szkło mnie nie ochroni.
I'd rather be hung than be eaten by those monsters!
Już lepiej mnie powieście.
It's fine!
Spokojnie.
Don't worry.
Nie martw się.
It's thick bullet-proof glass.
To kuloodporne szkło.
And soundproof to boot.
I dźwiękoszczelne.
Let's begin.
Zaczynamy.
Fukami-san, please enter.
Fukami-san, proszę wejść.
Okay.
Okej.
Hey, Uragami.
Hej, Uragami.
Look at him!
Spójrz na niego.
Fine, fine.
Dobra.
What do you think, Fukami-san?
Co pan myśli, Fukami-san?
Well, he is not a parasite.
To nie jest pasożyt.
He is responding slightly to my telepathy.
Reaguje nieco na moją telepatię.
He's walled his mind off,
Odgrodził swój umysł,
but I doubt he has the same ability as me.
ale raczej nie ma tych umiejętności, co ja.
He's talking up a good game.
To ciekawe.
I should explain beforehand
Powinnam wspomnieć,
that these self-proclaimed "psychics" in the room
że te samozwańcze „media” to prawdopodobnie sami oszuści.
Even if anyone had this superpo-- rather,
Jeśli ktokolwiek ma tu wyjątkowe umiejętności,
Well, Uragami?
I jak, Uragami?
A total fraud.
To oszust.
Tell this dweeb I said,
Możecie mu to przekazać.
"Show me a liar and I will show you a thief."
Kłamca i pewnie jeszcze złodziej.
Look who's talking!
I kto to mówi.
And he's a serial killer.
To seryjny morderca.
Next one, please.
Następny.
What's wrong, Uragami?
Co jest, Uragami?
You're cruel, Detective.
Jesteście okrutni.
You know the kind of life we lead in prison.
Wiecie, jak tu jest w więzieniu.
How could you put such a hottie in front of me?
A przyprowadzacie mi tu taką ślicznotkę.
Is he actually…
Czy on…?
We should probably stop him.
Powstrzymajmy go.
His focus may drop.
Może się rozkojarzyć.
There's no mistake!
Bez dwóch zdań.
This man's a parasite!
On jest pasożytem!
Hey, wait, pretty lady.
Poczekaj, ślicznotko.
What a joke.
To śmieszne.
Izumi-kun, thank you for waiting. Please go in.
Izumi-kun, proszę wejść.
Okay.
Okej.
You can't hear each other, so there's no need to hold back.
Nie słyszycie się nawzajem. Mów otwarcie.
What do you think of that man?
Co o nim myślisz?
What I think?
Co myślę?
I'm not sure.
Nie jestem pewien.
You seem to run into parasites often for some reason.
Z jakiegoś powodu miałeś częste kontakty z pasożytami.
This time, the parasite named Tamura Reiko approached you.
Ostatnim pasożytem, z jakim się widziałeś, była Tamura Reiko.
Perhaps you have something that attracts them.
Być może jest w tobie coś, co je przyciąga.
Or perhaps you have an ability to tell them apart?
A może potrafisz je rozpoznawać?
Calm down.
Spokojnie. Muszę się uspokoić, a wszystko będzie dobrze.
No.
Nie.
To me, it seems highly likely that you are the partner
Myślę, że to ty jesteś tym partnerem,
But mentioning Kuramori to you has no effect.
Ale wspominanie przy tobie Kuramoriego nie przynosi żadnego efektu.
I find it difficult to believe
Trudno mi uwierzyć,
that a normal high school student can keep lying with a straight face, but…
że zwyczajny licealista może być aż tak dobrym kłamcą.
Inspector, the bastard's asleep!
Ten gnój zasnął!
What?
Co?
Hey, Uragami!
Uragami!
Wake up!
Obudź się!
I guess I used up my energy. Huh?
Ta laska mnie wyczerpała.
You have a cute face, baby boy.
Ładny z ciebie chłopiec.
If you dressed up as a woman, you might make good spank material.
Załóż sukienkę, to zwalę sobie drugi raz.
Hey, Detective.
Detektywie.
Tell him to look me right in the eye.
Niech on spojrzy mi w oczy.
Izumi-kun.
Izumi-kun.
Yes?
Tak?
Next time, "In Cold Blood."
Następny odcinek: „Z zimną krwią”